{
    "id": "dbbc7d2019fa48f7ab94193188c08ecd",
    "title": "Sentence Patterns Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "26788a6f1d2b41018d48a5201bc3fbb8",
            "title": "Sentence Patterns Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "It was careless …………………….. her to repeat that mistake.",
                    "description": "The adjective careless can be followed by ‘of + noun / pronoun + to-infinitive’.",
                    "answers": [
                        "of",
                        "for",
                        "with"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "It is wicked of him ………………………. such things.",
                    "description": "The adjective wicked can be followed by ‘of + noun / pronoun + to-infinitive’.",
                    "answers": [
                        "for saying",
                        "to say"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "It is no use …………………… about it.",
                    "description": "The pattern is ‘it + be + no use / good etc. + -ing form’.",
                    "answers": [
                        "to worry",
                        "worrying",
                        "for worrying"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "It is strange …………………………",
                    "description": "The pattern is: it + be + adjective / noun + that clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "for him to behave like that",
                        "that he should have behaved like that",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "It is a pity ……………………………..",
                    "description": "The pattern is: it + be + adjective / noun + that clause",
                    "answers": [
                        "that you could not pass the test",
                        "for you not to pass the test",
                        "of you not to pass the test"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "She was too arrogant …………………… to me.",
                    "description": "Note the pattern ‘too…to’.",
                    "answers": [
                        "for listening",
                        "to listen",
                        "to listening"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "She was stupid enough ………………… him.",
                    "description": "The pattern is: adjective / adverb + enough + to-infinitive",
                    "answers": [
                        "that she trusted",
                        "to trust",
                        "for trusting"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I was so tired …………………………. any further.",
                    "description": "The pattern is: so + adjective / adverb + that – clause",
                    "answers": [
                        "to walk",
                        "that I could walk",
                        "that I could not walk further"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "What a charming girl ………………………..!",
                    "description": "The pattern is: what + adjective + noun + subject + verb",
                    "answers": [
                        "is she",
                        "she is",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "…………………………….. tall you have grown!",
                    "description": "In exclamatory sentences we use ‘how’ before adjectives without nouns.",
                    "answers": [
                        "How",
                        "What",
                        "What a"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "If I find your watch, I …………………………… it to you.",
                    "description": "In first conditional sentences, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + infinitive in the main clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "will give",
                        "would give",
                        "would have given"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "How …………………….. he plays!",
                    "description": "Well is an adverb. We need an adverb to modify a verb (play)",
                    "answers": [
                        "good",
                        "well"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}